Contact

satif04@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/satif04 (LinkedIn)

www.elyncsoft.com (Company) sccm.elyncsoft.com (Blog) tech15.elyncsoft.com (Blog)

Top Skills

Linux System Administration SCCM System Deployment

Languages

Urdu (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)
Arabic (Limited Working)

Certifications

MCP

LPIC Level I

MCSE Server Infrastructure

Microsoft Specialist - Configuring Windows Devices

Configuring Microsoft Windows Devices

Honors-Awards

BDD Consultant (MCS)
Systems Engineer (PERN II)
Technical Consultant & Trainer

Publications

LAMP Stack

Atif Ahmed

Systems Consultant | Cyber Security Researcher Pakistan

Summary

Sr. Technical Consultant on Linux, VMware and Microsoft Technologies and Cyber Security Professional on LAN, EPN, WAN and WLAN Networks with a strong interest in ethical hacking, penetration testing, vulnerability analysis, and network security. Offering 13 years of managerial and technical background on Linux, VMware and Microsoft Solutions. Specializing in domestic and global deployments of Linux Infrastructure and Microsoft Products. I have designed and implemented Server's Infrastructure Projects throughout Oman, Middle East and West African Regions and have a real-world solutions experience with some of the largest enterprises. I have used several Linux Distributions on my variety of projects including Linux Mint, Debian, Ubuntu, Kali Linux, MX Linux, CentOS, Fedora and Others. I enjoy teaching others and share my knowledge about how to use and exploit the power of Linux Operating System and apply those core Linux skills to break into Systems and Networks. Currently in a Cybersecurity role where I continue to develop and learn new abilities while contributing to the overall success of the organization

Capacity Building:

- Conducted Ethical Hacking Bootcamp at LyncSoft
- Presented Microsoft Intune Live Demos at Pearl Continental Karachi
- Presented Azure Site Recovery Live Showcase Demo at Pearl Continental Karachi
- Conducted SCCM Current Branch Boot Camp at Onwire Technologies
- Presented OMS and Advance Threat Analytics at Mövenpick Karachi
- Conducted Microsoft Windows 10 Bootcamp at NED University Of Engineering & Technology
- Hosted a Workshop on SCCM for "Capacity Building Of IT Staff" in HEC Head Office (Islamabad) published including in the HEC News
 Views Magazine

- SCCM deployment and migration projects from ranging several 100 to over 25,000 users
- MTN Nigeria BDD Project Team Lead
- Have an honour and privilege to work on more than 35+ different kinds of Operating Systems.

Areas of Expertise:

- Leadership
- Linux Package Management and Patch Management
- Linux Deployment, Up-gradation and Migrations
- LAMP Stack
- Bash Scripting
- Cyber Security
- Penetration Testing with Kali Linux, Parrot Security, BlackArch
- Python
- Vagrant, Ansible
- SCCM and Intune Deployment & Migrations
- Microsoft Infrastructure Design
- Systems Administration (Linux, Windows, OS X)
- Virtualization
- Vendor Management
- UAT Management
- Web Development
- Training

For Business Inquiries, Training & Consultancy Services: Please contact at atif@elyncsoft.com or via Linkedin InMail

Experience

LyncSoft

Cyber Security Consultant April 2015 - Present (5 years 2 months)

Microsoft

Partner Seller (Enterprise Mobility + Security)
May 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 4 months)
Pakistan

Drive a strong co-sell motion with Microsoft.

Access to exclusive content and deep engagement with Microsoft teams

Unique access to Microsoft Full Time Employee (FTE) enablement and the Microsoft-endorsed Partner Seller credential.

Invited on Partner Seller Meetups and Conferences

Full Access to the Microsoft Corporate Network

International Office Products
Senior Technical Consultant
December 2016 - July 2018 (1 year 8 months)

Responsible for detailed Plan, Design and Implementation of Advance System Center Solutions for prospective clients as well as provide cloud based solution on Microsoft Azure Platform such as EMS, OMS, Azure Site Recovery and Azure Backup.

KalSoft Limited Sr. IS Consultant October 2013 - March 2014 (6 months) Pakistan

SCCM Planning, Deployment

SCCM Proposals

Research and Implementation

Create, change, and delete user accounts per request.

Repair and recover from hardware or software failures.

Coordinate and communicate with impacted constituencies.

Apply OS patches and upgrades on a regular basis, and upgrade administrative tools and utilities. Configure / add new services as necessary. Perform ongoing performance tuning, hardware upgrades, and resource optimization as required. Configure CPU, memory, and disk partitions as required.

Maintain data center environmental and monitoring equipment.

MHD Infotech LLC
Microsoft Consultant
September 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 2 months)
Oman (Muscat)

Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft System Center 2012 Suite throughout Oman Region.

Responsible for formal sign off on all System Center Project deliverables
Responsible for Bill All Signed-off Microsoft Infrastructure Projects throughout
Oman Region

Responsible for Pre-Sales and Post-Sales of System Center Suite throughout Oman Region

Responsible for Meeting with Prospective Clients
Responsible for delivering RFP, Techincal Proposal as per requirement of prospective customers

International Office Products
Technology Specialist
March 2012 - August 2012 (6 months)
Karachi

Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft System Center 2012 Suit throughout Pakistan Region.

MetalSoft

Infrastructure Consultant November 2010 - January 2012 (1 year 3 months)

Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft projects throughout Pakistan. Responsible for the entire IT division, including the management of Sales, Pre Sales and Post Sales of all existing and upcoming accounts. Responsible for all the problems resolutions pertaining to ongoing projects. Handled all escalations related to the IT projects. Provided pre sales, post sales and technical support for regional customers Accompanied sales staff on meetings with prospective customers to discuss the viability and feasibility of the proposed solution and/or upcoming opportunities.

Higher Education Commission
System Engineer (PERN2)
September 2009 - October 2010 (1 year 2 months)

Responsible of Designing, Implementing and Maintaining of AD and SCCM 2007 R2 Infrastructure.

Kalsoft

2 years 10 months

Infrastructure Services Consultant November 2006 - January 2009 (2 years 3 months)

Responsible for all the problems resolutions pertaining to ongoing projects.

Handled all escalations related to the IT Projects. Provided pre sales and technical support for regional customers. Meetings with prospective customers

to discuss the viability and feasibility of the proposed solution and/or upcoming opportunities.

Systems Infrastructure Engineer April 2006 - October 2006 (7 months)

Responsible of Designing, Implementing, Maintaining and Managing of large and complex Infrastructure Projects.

Education

Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology BS, Compuer System Engineering · (2002 - 2006)